MUHAMMAD DZULKARNAEN BIN SHAMSUDDIN

Putrajaya · 012-4440297

muhammad.dzulkarnaen@outlook.com · linkedin.com/in/muhammad-dzulkarnaen

Experienced Software Engineer with a demonstrated history of working in the information services industry. Skilled in .NET, SQL Scripting, Web Application Development, API Integration and RPA. Strong software engineering professional with a bachelor's degree focused on Computer Science from Universiti Tenaga Nasional.

EXPERIENCE

AUG 2018 – PRESENT ANALYST PROGRAMMER,

EXPERIAN

- Developed and implemented solutions that increase the level of automation and efficiency of the business unit.
- Worked on multiple projects simultaneously and participated in the whole software development process from design to implementation and delivery.
- Tested and supported existing applications and using my own knowledge and expertise made improvement suggestions.
- Responsible to remediate the vulnerabilities in the applications which are founded by Veracode and manual penetration test.
- Lead an empower project to automate operation team process using RPA and competed in a Hackaton at the global level.
- Awarded employee of the month twice for performing great work.

MAY 2018 - AUG 2018

EXECUTIVE SOFTWARE ENGINEER,

HUMAN RESOURCES DEVELOPMENT CORPORATION (HRD CORP)

- Involved in requirements gathering process with the user as well as the designing.
- Developed an in-house application that is used for reporting by several departments in the company.
- Created a script used to extract data based on ad-hoc needs.
- Participated in the network proxy meeting with the vendor.

FEB 2017 - MAY 2018

SOFTWARE ENGINEER,

CREATIVE SYSTEM CONSULTANT SDN BHD

- Participated in the whole software development process from requirement gathering until the delivery to the users.
- Responsible to design and development of database and web application.
- Used self-taught skills to create a stored procedures and advance SQL scripting.
- Responsibilities quickly grew to lead the migration of Tekun application database from Oracle to SQL Server
- Provided code advising to the colleagues.

EDUCATION

2015 - 2017

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE (SOFTWARE ENGINEERING) (HONS),

UNIVERSITI TENAGA NASIONAL (UNITEN) (CGPA: 3.78)

Equipped me with the necessary knowledge and skills in requirements engineering, operating systems, mobile application development, data and computer security, artificial intelligence, and other related areas. Awarded dean list for every semester. The final year project (Rent-It-Easy) was designed and built using Android, Google Firebase, and GeoFire. Participated in MSTB Test Design Competition, MDEC Big-Data Workshop, UNITEN Integrity Health Competition, and Hope Worldwide Organization. Program committee for Pro-C Programming Competition.

2009 - 2012

HIGHER NATIONAL DIPLOMA IN SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT,

KOLEJ PROFESIONAL MARA (CGPA: 3.76)

Awarded dean list for every semester. Built an application (Ko-Q Tracking System) for the college co-curricular department that can import CSV files into the database. Allow the user to search by Student ID and track all the student co-curricular activity for every semester. Build on .NET and using MySQL database.

SKILLS

- .NET Framework / Core
- Visual Studio / Visual Studio Code
- SQL Scripting (SQL Server, Oracle, MySQL)
- SOAP
- REST
- Written and oral fluency in Malay and English
- Azure DevOps
- MVC and Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)
- XML / JSON
- SVN and Git
- Razor, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript and JQuery
- Automation Anywhere Robotic Process Automation (RPA)

ACTIVITIES

Due to the job nature of a programmer which is mainly to sit in front of a laptop, I enjoy doing cardio such as cycling, running or jump rope either before I start to work, after working hours or during the weekends. I also enjoy travelling, observed and experienced other cultures. Get to exercised extensive problem-solving and cross-cultural communication skills during travelling. Learned how to adapt to unanticipated situations and improvise new plans due to periodic travel mishaps and unexpected events. Recently, participated in the department running challenges.